Cash, cash,
cash for your bones!
Too many bones? Not enough
cash? Call Cash Bone!
Ribs, skulls, spines,
even certain tiny ear bones.
The leg bone's connected to the Cash Bone!
Aw! Nibbler made
a bobo for Mama.
I'll pick it up with my
supey-dupey poopy scoopy.
Core magnetic field,
31 microteslas.
Nice.
Temperature? Whoa!
The magma P. I. is 10,000 degrees Selleck!
Leela, I am
collecting data.
Could you dump that
somewhere else?
Not really. It's highly volatile
dark matter and some corn.
But I'm presenting
my thesis tomorrow,
and I've barely
had time to prepare.
Nonsense. You've been my
grad student for 12 years.
You were ready
six years ago.
What?
I probably
should have told you.
Anyway, the important thing
is to be relaxed tomorrow.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Do what you young
people do to unwind.
Take a joyride
in your jalopy.
Wear a T-shirt and eat a fish stick. Go!
Okay, amigos, one teensy drink to help Amy relax.
Hear, hear!
Hmm.
I guess I'm still
kind of nervous.
One more teensy drink
to help Amy relax.
Still a little
nervous?
She's a nervous wreck!
Well, I may not
have a man,
but at least I've got you, poopsie-doodle.
Leela, it's time
you and I had a talk.
A talk? You can't break up
with me. You're my pet!
As much as I enjoy being the
object of your misplaced affections,
I am also a highly
sophisticated being
who longs for intelligent conversation.
Aw! Is shnookums not feeling shtimuwated?
An understatement,
to say the least.
It's time you treated me with respect.
If you want to be treated like
a fellow crew member, fine,
but no more
purse rides,
and no more dressing you up in
your cute little sailor suit.
I keep telling you that's my real naval uniform.
Your place or mine?
Both. But first,
this place.
Ooh! Room for one more?
I thought
I set you for 7:15!
Sorry, I hooked up with Bender last night.
Dude was all over
my snooze button.
But my doctoral exam
is in 10 minutes. On Mars!
Ew! Kif, did you
yack on the floor?
Yes, I did.
Where's your candidate,
Farnsworth?
I have a long list of students to humiliate today.
You're late,
Miss Wong.
Oh, God, this is like
one of those nightmares!
Here, take my lab coat.
Allow me to introduce
your examining committee
in descending order
of grumpiness.
Professor
Ogden Wernstrom.
Wernstrom.
Downtown Professor of Applied
Physics, Ethan "Bubblegum" Tate.
I see by your curriculum vitae
that you're a Sagittarius.
And Professor
Fisherprice Shpeekenshpell.
The cow says...
He proved that 50 years ago, and
he's been coasting on it ever since.
I am the esteemed Professor Morris
Katz, and you are wasting my time.
Proceed.
Imagine,
if you will...
Oh, God.
A gigantic spherical generator, one
that could provide unlimited energy
because it's essentially
in perpetual motion.
Young lady, have you been drinking?
Well, yes,
but that's not revelant.
I'm talking about Earth.
Earth's the generator.
Suppose this basketball
is the whole world.
To many young men
in the inner city, it is.
As it spins, it's producing
an enormous magnetic field.
If we could use that field
to generate electric current,
we could actually harness the
Earth's rotational ener... Ener...
Yes, tapping the Earth's ener-kerchoo.
Go on.
Sorry, I'm super-allergic to cats.
Professor Katz,
would you mind...
Miss Wong,
I mind everything.
You just need to polarize the
Earth's core with a huge static charge
by ratcheting superconducting wire down into...
Sorry.
Enough. The committee members
will now vote yea or nay.
Nay.
Hell, nay.
The horse says,
"Doctorate denied".
It's okay, Amy.
I don't have
a fancy degree either,
but today I'm a prominent boy
in the package delivery field.
Now that I am a full
and equal member of the crew,
I pledge my loyalty,
my perspicacity
and, dare I say it,
my friendship.
Leela, muzzle
that skunk.
We can't stop a meeting for
some cute, fuzzy, little...
Hey,
look, a kitty cat.
You again?
Get away,
you mangy ball of histamines.
You leave
kitty cat alone!
Kitty cat.
People, please, I'm trying to run a business,
so I get to hold kitty.
Here, puss, puss...
No, me. Over here. I wanna hold him.
Its anus looks
like an asterisk.
Captain Fuzzy Toes reporting
for duty. I mean, cutie.
My best friend died
in that uniform.
I hate that cat!
If I had a spray bottle,
I'd give him such a spritzing.
I'll tell you one thing,
nothing acts that cute
without some ulterior motive.
Aw! You want
your dipey changed?
We'll have to watch
its every move.
Powder, please.
Here's my new theory:
That is one adorable cat.
I guess
I was just jealous.
I do miss being
Leela's shnookums.
I'm going to apologize
and hope for a pity pet.
Yes, my lord.
Amy and Nibbler
are a tewwible thweat.
They must be spayed
and neutered, wespectivewy.
The cat is evil!
We have proof!
It was summoning
a saucer.
Of course it wanted a saucer, you idiot.
A saucer of
dewicious cweam.
You fool, this isn't
about the cream!
It's pwonounced
"cweam"!
I'm petting mine
down to the bone.
Just stwoke
its fwuffy fur.
Scwatch its fwubby chin.
Fweeble its fwooby pwow.
Pet it. Pet it.
No, no!
What do cats need with that much yarn and cobalt?
They're doing something downstairs.
We've got to find out what.
Where do you think
you're going, No-cat?
The basement. I think I
left the air hockey table on.
Without a cat,
you ain't going nowhere.
Can you at least tell us
what's going on down there?
We're certainly not building something sinister,
if that's what
you're implying.
Now, come on, Bender, something
sinister won't build itself.
Professor Katz's
last name is Katz.
Do you think he has something
to do with these cats?
The conclusion is as inescapable as it is moronic.
I say we pay him a visit,
and if he won't talk to us,
he'll talk to
Smith & Wesson
or, perhaps,
Consolidated Head Melter.
Professor Katz,
we want answers!
I warn you, if I have to get
cute, it's gonna get ugly.
He's dead!
Wait. What are these
strings on his lap?
What the...
He isn't dead.
He's one of those
dog-operated puppets
that's been adapted
for use by a cat!
So, I had my doctorate
denied by that fuzzball?
Bad kitty!
They actually built the
planetary ratchet from my thesis!
Uh-oh!
What the...
Well, look what
the me dragged in.
You can talk!
You can talk?
How ironic.
Two hyper-intelligent beings both
pretending to be simple house pets.
Say, do you know
Obliteron?
He pretends to be
a hamster, but...
Yeah, that's really great. Could
you please tell us what's going on?
What? Oh! Right.
You see, my associates and I
are from the ninth planet
of the star
you call Thuban.
Long ago,
life there was ideal.
The sun provided plenty of warm, dozy light.
The chicken-salmon
roamed free.
Yet disaster loomed.
Our planet's rotation
was gradually slowing.
At first,
it seemed beneficial.
Long, dark nights
for sleeping,
long, sunny days
for sleeping.
But then it got too hot.
And too cold.
Our top scientists
went to work.
At last, they located a planet
with the necessary orientation
and magnetic field to
harness its rotational energy.
Earth!
Indubitably.
Although we call it
Blue Blue Shiny Ball.
In the area
now known as Egypt,
my people constructed a
giant, semi-octahedral antenna
to beam Earth's rotational energy to Thuban.
The Great
Pyramid at Giza!
Yes. The Egyptians
viewed us as gods,
but ironically,
that was our downfall.
They pampered us with feasts most
fancy and victuals most tender.
We grew fat
and domesticated.
Thousands of years passed,
and our home world was nearing total destruction.
Shut up!
But the technology
to save our planet was lost.
Lost, that is, until I heard
you speak at Mars University.
So, you called my thesis a fat sack
of barf, and then you stole it?
Welcome to academia.
He intends to siphon off
Earth's rotational energy!
Earth will come
to a stop, and...
Half of you will cook,
and half of you will freeze.
Earth will be one big McDLT. We
just got that commercial last year.
Oh, yeah, smarty paws?
You may have built the ratchet,
but you can't reach the core
without 4,000 miles
of superconducting wire.
The ball of yarn!
Quite.
Even so, you'd still need a
tremendously powerful static charge
to trigger the process.
Ever had a cat
rub up against you?
If you're propositioning me,
I'm not interested.
I'm talking about
the charge generated
when 50,000 felines rub against a single surface.
Professor?
Soon the world
will come to a stop,
and there's nothing
you can do to stop it.
The stopping of the world,
that is. It's unstoppable.
Excuse me.
The Earth is
coming to a stop!
Keep your eyes on
the kitties and push!
These space cats seem to be employing
some form of hypnotic hyper-cuteness.
Well, two can play at that
game. And one of them is me.
Nibbler? Poopsie-doodle?
Mr. Winkles, Smudge-Smudge.
Quick, dance with each other!
Aw!
Damn, they are good.
We're coming to a full stop.
All cats, to your posts!
Catastrophe Beach Party.
Scene One.
Cue disaster effects,
and action!
Cut! That extra looked at the
camera. We'll have to do it again.
And now to transfer your
planet's rotational energy
to my home world.
Well, now, this calls for a celebration.
What's all this cat
hair on my sweater?
Why am I full of sand?
And Tootsie Rolls?
You were all under the spell
of those obnoxious space cats!
Enjoy being broiled alive by the sun,
and also the dead bird
we've left in your slipper.
Quickly! If we turn
the ratchet the other way,
perhaps we can
restart the Earth!
It won't turn.
Push harder, Bender!
I can't! You should have
called my cousin, Turner.
It's hopeless.
Even in theory, the device can
only apply force in one direction.
Can someone open a window? It's
getting a little warm in here.
Is that better?
Shmeezus, it's hot!
Why'd I have to invent
that awful device?
Amy, technology isn't
intrinsically good or evil.
It's how it's used.
Like the death ray.
Maybe you're right.
I guess science has to keep pushing
forward with the hope that...
That's it!
Pushing forward!
Professor, I know how
to restart the Earth!
You can't
suddenly know something
just by assembling
a committee of words.
That's it!
I'll assemble your committee!
The ratchet
won't turn backwards,
but what if we kept
pushing it forward?
Earth would start
turning again!
Yes, the wrong direction!
So?
Gentlemen, ladies, let's get this globe trotting.
It's working!
Just a little faster!
But we're plotzing here!
Then look at Nibbler!
Aw!
On the whole, Earth's society is worthless.
But they do have
these things called
antique rugs that are
great for peeing on.
Good show.
And though the world is now spinning in
the wrong direction, it's good enough.
Well done, Amy.
I'm honored to begrudgingly
present you with your Ph. D.
in applied physics.
Also, some kind of sportsmanship
award I had in my glove compartment.
Yay! I'm finally done with
school! How's the job market?
Rough.
Congratulations,
Dr. Wong!
Congratulations.
Permission
to come aboard?
Granted, shnookums.
You've got
a bright future, Amy.
As sure as the sun
sets in the east.